<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>neuro | Sebastian Sauer Academic</title>
    <link>https://sebastiansauer-academic.netlify.app/tag/neuro/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://sebastiansauer-academic.netlify.app/tag/neuro/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>neuro</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://sebastiansauer-academic.netlify.app/media/icon_hufe30330db5c3dae5647fd2ef1714014b_368463_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>neuro</title>
      <link>https://sebastiansauer-academic.netlify.app/tag/neuro/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real-time Prediction of User Performance based on Pupillary Assessment via Eye Tracking</title>
      <link>https://sebastiansauer-academic.netlify.app/publication/ais-hci-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sebastiansauer-academic.netlify.app/publication/ais-hci-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Abstract&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We propose a method to predict user performance based on eye-tracking. The method uses eye-tracking-based pupillometry to capture pupil diameter data and calculates—based on a Random Forest algorithm—user performance expectations. We conducted a large-scale experimental evaluation (125 participants aged from 21 to 61 years) and found promising results that pave the way for a dynamic real-time adaption of IT to a user’s mental effort and expected user performance. We have already achieved a good classification accuracy of user performance after only 40 seconds (5% of the mean total trial time that our participants took to complete our experiment). The non-invasive contact-free method can be applied cost-efficiently both in research and practical environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keywords: NeuroIS, user performance, mental effort, pupillometry, eye-tracking, Random Forest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    This paper was awarded in 2018 with an Best Paper Award by the Journal &lt;a href=&#34;https://aisel.aisnet.org/thci/awards.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Transactions of Human-Computer Interaction&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
