<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>machinelearing | Sebastian Sauer Academic</title>
    <link>https://sebastiansauer-academic.netlify.app/tag/machinelearing/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://sebastiansauer-academic.netlify.app/tag/machinelearing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>machinelearing</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://sebastiansauer-academic.netlify.app/media/icon_hufe30330db5c3dae5647fd2ef1714014b_368463_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>machinelearing</title>
      <link>https://sebastiansauer-academic.netlify.app/tag/machinelearing/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Most healthcare interventions tested in Cochrane Reviews are not effective according to high quality evidence: a systematic review and meta-analysis</title>
      <link>https://sebastiansauer-academic.netlify.app/publication/astra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sebastiansauer-academic.netlify.app/publication/astra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Abstract&lt;/em&gt;
The effectiveness of most cancer targeted therapies is short-lived. Tumors often develop resistance that might be overcome with drug combinations. However, the number of possible combinations is vast, necessitating data-driven approaches to find optimal patient-specific treatments. Here we report AstraZeneca’s large drug combination dataset, consisting of 11,576 experiments from 910 combinations across 85 molecularly characterized cancer cell lines, and results of a DREAM Challenge to evaluate computational strategies for predicting synergistic drug pairs and biomarkers. 160 teams participated to provide a comprehensive methodological development and benchmarking. Winning methods incorporate prior knowledge of drug-target interactions. Synergy is predicted with an accuracy matching biological replicates for &amp;gt;60% of combinations. However, 20% of drug combinations are poorly predicted by all methods. Genomic rationale for synergy predictions are identified, including ADAM17 inhibitor antagonism when combined with PIK3CB/D inhibition contrasting to synergy when combined with other PI3K-pathway inhibitors in PIK3CA mutant cells.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
